<Document>
  [color=lightblue][bold]OOC[/bold]: You can view the guidebook externally by using the link on our discord.[/color]

  # Nanotrasen Law

  Nanotrasen's overarching laws that security teams are hired to enforce. Any persons or vessels in an NT controlled sector are required to follow these laws.


  ## Treatment of Prisoners
  
  All prisoners or persons in custody are subject to the same treatment.
  
  - Prisoners must be given clothing and edible food/drink if requested.
  - Prisoners must be contained in a safe area, if their current confinement cell is unfit for life they are to be escorted to the next best location.
  - Prisoners must have all their confiscated belongings returned to them upon release, unless they are illegal or were used to commit a crime.
  - Prisoners must have access to communications equipment, unless they abuse it after warnings.
  - Prisoners must not be restrained while in a safe cell, unless they pose a threat to life or limb.
  - Prisoners must be given medical aid upon request or inability to request it due to medical reasons, unless they pose a threat to life or limb.
  - Prisoners must be given legal or spiritual counseling upon request if available, unless they pose a threat to life or limb.
  
  
  ## Searches and Confiscation

  There are three defined searches; Personal Searches, Custody Searches, and Department Searches. Each has their own specifications on what's being searched and when they can be performed.

  - Personal Searches
  
  A personal search is limited to one person and includes a search of their belongings for any illegal items. Common procedure is to search in any pockets, bags, and coats, then confiscate any illegal items. However if there's reason to search other objects like their radio, PDA, or boots, these may be done at the searching officer's discretion.

  To perform a personal search one of three requirements must be met; the searching officer has a properly filed search warrant, the personnel's Head of Staff approves and accompanies the officer during their search, or the facility's alert level is blue or higher.

  - Custody Searches
  
  A custody search is limited to one person and includes a search of their belongings for any illegal items, or equipment used in a crime. Common procedure is to perform a full and thorough search of their gear and person, then confiscate any illegal items or equipment that was used to commit a crime. However it is ultimately up to the searching officer's discretion as to how in-depth the search is.
  
  To perform a custody search one of two requirements must be met; the person being searched is currently in custody for a crime, or an officer witnessed the person commit a crime themselves while they are not currently in custody.

  - Department Searches
  
  A department search is limited to an entire department's physical area and its staff, this includes a search of any involved department staff's belongings and objects inside the involved department area for any illegal items. Common procedure is to gather all involved personnel into the same room, perform a personal search on all of them, hold them in the room while the rest of the department is being searched, and then confiscate any illegal items. However it is ultimately up to the leading officer's discretion on how the search is executed.

  To perform a department search one of two requirements must be met; the searching officers have a properly filed department search warrant, or the Head of the involved department approves and accompanies the officers on their search.

  -Vessel Searches
  
  A vessel search is limited to a vessel and its occupants, this includes a search of any known crew's belongings and objects inside the vessel for any illegal items. Procedure is much like a departmental search however extra caution should be exercised due to the mobile nature of vessels.

  To perform a vessel search one of three requirements must be met; One of the vessel's crewmembers have been arrested for a crime and there is reasonable belief that searching their vessel will assist with security's investigation of the crime, there is reasonable belief that the crew is hiding stolen items, contraband items, kidnapped individuals, or known criminals on their vessel, or an owner of the vessel approves and accompanies the officers on their search.
  
  
  ## Detainments, Arrests, and Interrogations

  Security, High Command, or Central Command ranking personnel are authorized to act with the authority to detain, arrest, and interrogate any person so long as they are acting lawfully. The Head of Security, Captain, and any Central Command personnel may deputize anyone with one of more of these authorizations at their discretion.

  - Detainment: The temporary holding of someone outside of the brig for their safety, the safety of others, investigative purposes, or for the arrival of arresting authorized personnel. Anyone who shows signs of being an imminent threat to themselves or others, is obstructing or encroaching on a security scene, is being searched, or has been witnessed committing a crime by the detainer may be detained by any authorized persons. The detainment may only last up until the situation is now clear for them to undetained. Someone may be detained and forcefully moved to another safe and public location if it would prove more useful than keeping them detained for the entire duration of the situation.

  - Arrest: The act of bringing a criminal into custody to charge them with a crime and sentence them. Anyone who has been confirmed to have committed a crime may be arrested by any authorized persons. An arrest ends once the criminal is in the brig and being processed.

  - Interrogation: The act of holding and forcefully questioning someone for investigative purposes. Anyone who is believed to have committed a crime, be linked to a crime, or have witnessed a crime may be interrogated by any authorized persons, so long as there is an interrogation warrant approving such an act. Interrogations may be held wherever the interrogating officer sees best fit. Interrogations are to conclude in accordance with the written warrant, however the interrogated person may opt to continue afterwards for as long as they desire. Interrogations may not be conducted in unlawful ways, be it through the use of violence or inflicting extreme mental distress. Anyone who is confirmed to have been intentionally lying during an interrogation may be charged with fraud.
  
  
  ## Warrants

  Warrants are signed permits giving authorization to do one of two things; search a person/place, or interrogate a person. All permits must detail who/what is being searched/interrogated, the officer(s) conducting the procedure, the general reason that led to the warrant's existence, the general time the warrant is approved for use, and when the procedure concludes or expires. Warrants may not be held from those involved if they ask for a copy of them

  Who can approve a warrant is determined by the type. If one of the conducting officers is someone who is capable of approving the warrant then the warrant can only get approved by one of their superiors.

  - Search Warrants: A signed permit giving authorization to search a specific person or location in accordance with the type of search it is. Personal searches can only be approved by the Warden, the HoS, or the Captain. Department searches can only be approved by the Head of the related department or the Captain. When a search warrant concludes may be listed as a time frame or things such as upon the leading officer's discretion or once every room and person has been cleared.

  - Interrogation Warrants: A signed permit giving authorization to hold and forcefully question a person. An interrogation warrant can only be approved by the Warden, the HoS, or the Captain. An interrogation warrant can only last for a timed duration, upwards to an hour after the interrogation begins.
  
  
  ## Implant Procedures

  Any prisoner in custody can be subjected to implantation or implant removal procedures, so long as it's within reason. The process of adding an implant should not prolong the detainees sentence, meaning you can not hold them longer to administer the implant. A former inmate can be requested to undergo implantation at a later point in time, upwards of a day, if they fit the requirements during their confinement, if they refuse they can be forced to comply. Implants can only be force administered with the Head of Security or Captain's permission. A prisoner can still receive implantation without meeting the requirements if they give their clear permission.

  At this point in time the only implant that is authorized for forced implantation are security tracking implants, which may be administered to anyone who has been convicted of breach of custody or a crime involving direct intentional harm to themself to others.

  ### Removal

  A suspect can be forced to receive implant removal if there is strong reasonable proof that they possess an illegal implant, such as an officer seeing them use one or their prints being on a discarded injector. Unlike implantation procedure a prisoner can have their sentence entirely delayed or extended until they comply with the procedure, as long as security are actively making attempts to perform it. Akin to implanting, if an inmate gives their clear permission, implant removal can proceed without proof.
  
  
  ## Sentencing

  All sentencing except warnings should be handled by the warden, however if there is no warden or they are neglecting their duty, the chain of succession is in this order: Head of Security > Senior Officer > Security Staff > Captain > Head of Personnel. The person handling sentencing may at their discretion designate any security staff to take care of a sentencing matter on their behalf. If deemed fit and reasonable the Head of Security may overrule any sentence issued, the Captain reserves the same right to overrule however they may also overrule the Head of Security.

  Sentences should only be as harsh as needed. The sentencing officer should use their discretion to charge according to the severity of each crime committed. Issuing someone the maximum punishment for a crime or a series of crimes should only be done if absolutely necessary.

  Sentences should be processed within a reasonable time frame. Generally once a criminal is brought into the brig the sentencing officer should start keeping track of how long they have been in the brig and deduct that from their sentence once the sentencing process has been completed, a rough estimation will also work if required.## Controlled Substances
  
  ### Clauses
  
  - Stackable Crimes: When working with timed confinement, crimes are to be considered 'stackable' in the sense that if you charge someone with two or more unique crimes, you should add up the times you would give them for each crime for a total final sentence. Linked crimes are generally evolutions of each other and can not be stacked. Linked crimes instead override each other and you should pick the highest crime that matches the case. For example; if you're giving someone 2 minutes of confinement for theft and 5 for assault, you would add up the time for a 7 minute confinement duration. For another example; If someone commits Trespass and Secure Trespass, you can only charge them with Secure Trespass because they're linked crimes.
  
  - Repeat Offenders: When working with timed confinement, a person is charged with a repeated crime if they have committed and been taken into custody for the type of crime in question in the past. Repeated crimes may be used to tack-on time to someone's confinement sentence if desired. Each instance of repeated crime adds 3 minutes to someone's sentence, additionally, this tacked-on time stacks with other repeated crimes, for example if this is a person's third theft then up to 6 minutes can be added to their sentence, plus 3 minutes if this was their second assault charge.

  - Accessory, Attempting, And Intention: If someone intentionally, knowingly and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime they can be charged with the relevant crimes, such as an engineer giving someone who says they are going to break into an area the tools to do so. Same goes for a clear and solid attempt at a crime, or a person who shows clear intent to act out a crime, for example a person attempting to take a hostage but being taken into custody midway through can still be charged with hostage taking.

  - Court: Any person charged with a punishment aside from a warning or a timed confinement sentence may request a trial from Central Command during the duration of their sentence, which will be handled in due time under Central protocol. Alternatively, the person may opt to try and get all involved parties in agreement for a non-Central court case, however a critical party may refuse to take part for any reason and if they are irreplaceable in the case then a non-Central trial is impossible.
  
  
  ## Punishments
  
  - Warning: The lowest punishment, a warning can be issued in place of any other punishment and is simply a clear warning to the perpetrator that continued illegal action will result in heavier sentencing.

  - Confinement: Confinement in the station's general population brig for a set duration. If there is reasonable belief that putting a prisoner in the general population brig would be unsafe for others, a different cell may be used. Any belongings of confined persons may be confiscated and stored securely till the prisoner is released.

  - Permanent Custody: A confinement sentence that does not end until decided upon by the Head of Security, Captain, or Central Command.

  - Psychiatric Custody: A looser confinement sentence that does not end until decided upon by the Chief Medical Officer, Captain, or Central Command. The person in custody does not need to be confined within the general population brig if deemed safe and preferable for medical personnel. The person in custody is to receive physiological assessment and help during the duration of their sentence. This sentence can not be applied if there are no medical personnel willing to perform the task.

  - Deportation: The forced transport of a person from station bounds to another facility due to inability to confine them safely. This sentence can only be applied if Central Command signs off on it.

  - Execution: A legal and humane way of dealing with severely problematic persons. The sentenced person may make a request at how they are executed, if it is deemed possible within a reasonable amount of time, security must comply with their wishes. Removal of one's brain to instead be placed in an NT cyborg has been deemed a reasonable execution request. This sentence can only be applied if the Captain and Head of Security both sign off on it.
  
  
  ## Crimes

  Crimes that involve a direct specific victim are only punishable if the victim opts to press charges; if the victim is left in a condition where they are unable to voice their opinion or refuse to then it is to be assumed that they opt to press charges. Additionally, crimes are not punishable if the person was acting in self defense against a reasonable threat or in a manner to rescue someone whose life was in imminent danger.

  The Max Sentencing per each crime will always list a maximum confinement time, however they may occasionally have alternative punishments listed. It is important to remember that you may only select one of the punishments under max sentencing. Warnings may always be issued in the place of any punishment.

  Other punishments that do not fall in line with a crime's Max Sentence may also be sought if it is deemed reasonable enough. For a bypass punishment to be processed Central Command must be made aware and approve of it.

  ### Crime Reference Tables
  
  [textlink="List of Crimes" link="CDCrimes"]

</Document>
