<Document>
  # Command

  The standard procedures followed by command staff on any uniform NT station. The Captain can edit, make additions, and make exceptions to their station's command operating procedures (excluding sections tagged with NE: non-editable) whenever they please as long as a copy of the changes is forwarded to each Heads of Staff's fax machine. Anyone considered a command member is required to follow this document, and their related work SOP if they have one.


  ## Departmental 2ICs

  The head of a department may authorize one of their staff members, typically their Senior, to act on their behalf in selected ways under chosen conditions. This system is officially known as departmental Second In Commands and is a largely free system for Heads of Staff to adjust to fit their liking. The only required step is that the command member fills out a form stating the chosen second in command, what authorizations they share, and under what circumstances, then sends it to the fax of their Captain. If no form is filled out and a department's head enters an unrecoverable state, it is assumed that the department's Senior is the 2IC and is automatically authorized field promotion to their respective Head of Staff position, The Captain may veto this if they see fit.


  ## Command Succession (NE)

  - 1. If there is no Captain, or the Captain is rendered out of service for an extended or permanent period of time, then the active Head of Personnel may choose to take up the position of Acting Captain or pick another capable Head of Staff for the role.

  - 2. If there is no Head of Personnel or they are deemed unable to work, then all active Head of Staff may hold a discussion amongst themselves and vote for an Acting Captain. The first Head to get 50% or more of the votes is to take the position.

  - 3. If there are no active Heads of Staff, then the first security staff to claim the role may have it. If it is in a time of emergency such as there being no Heads of Staff because they were all killed, then call the evacuation shuttle.

  - 4. If there are no security staff, then the first work authorized staff member to suggest themselves may take the role of Acting Captain. Like the step above, if it is a state of emergency the shuttle should be called instead.

  If a role from a step above your current status arrives at any point, the option of passing the role of Captain off to them should be offered. Such as security staff handing off acting captainship to the Head of Personnel once they arrive at station.


  ## Acting Captain

  The Acting Captain is a job bestowed only in the absence of an active and able Captain. Who the job is given to is determined by command succession.

  The Acting Captain's goal is similar to the Captain's in maintaining overall station order, directing in times of need, and ensuring their Heads are working well. The Acting Captain may choose to abandon their old duties to put full focus on their Acting Captainship or they may choose not to, it is up to them ultimately.

  Acting Captains are allowed Captain level access, the custom door remote, all communication channels, the nuclear authentication disk, a disabler, the Captain's sabre, stamp, carapace, and any Captain branded piece of clothing, nothing else should be removed from their wardrobe or locker. During red alert they are authorized access to the laser pistol.


  ## Captain Demotion (NE)

  The Captain can be demoted with a vote by the Heads of Staff. The majority of votes need to be against the Captain for the demotion to go through, if it is a tie it automatically favors the Captain. This can only be done if there are at least two Heads of Staff apart from the Captain. Once the Captain is demoted the chain of succession is to be followed to determine who takes charge.


  ## Staff Demotions (NE)

  To get any demotion to stick as a Head of Staff, you must send a stamped fax to your station's Central Oversight office very clearly explaining that it's a demotion record, who's being demoted, from what positions, and for how long. Failure to do so or deviation may result in the demotion not being properly processed and applied for future shifts.


  ## Station Binding

  Heads of Staff may not leave the station's proximity unless they are performing their regular duties or are granted permission by the Captain. The Captain may leave the station's proximity if they deem fit and inform the Head of Personnel, however both the Head of Personnel and Captain can not be absent from the station at the same time, one or the other must remain on board. This section can be ignored during emergency evacuation, crew transfers, or if ordered to by Central Command.
  
  Regular duties are defined by what the Captain deems reasonable in retrospect. Examples are things like;
  - Head of Securities responding to threats or boarding vessels.
  - Chief Engineers conducting repairs on nearby vessels.
  - Chief Medical Officers performing rescue operations.
  - Quartermasters going to the ATS.


  ## Uniform

  [color=green]Green[/color]: All heads of staff should be wearing at least one identifiable piece of their department's command insignia on them, while avoiding any other department's insignia that would cause confusion at a quick glance.

  [color=red]Red[/color]: All heads of staff should be wearing at least two identifiable pieces of their department's command insignia on them, no other departmental insignia or other attire that could conflict and cause confusion at a quick glance is allowed.

</Document>
