<Document>
  # Medical

  The standard procedures followed by medical staff on any uniform NT station. The Chief Medical Officer can edit, make additions, and make exceptions to their station's medical operating procedures whenever they please as long as a copy of the changes is forwarded to the Captain's fax machine and another laid out in the medical break room or other main room. The captain may veto any change made by the CMO if they see fit. Anyone considered under the medical department is required to follow this document.


 ## Treatment

  There are two primary types of medical care, emergency aid and full treatment. Failure to follow proper treatment procedure is considered endangerment to your patients.\n
  
  Treatment Types
  - Emergency aid is administered to ensure that a patient is not actively at risk, be it from their corpse rotting, or to get them out of a critical condition.
  - Full treatment is an effort to bring non-emergency patients to a full bill of health. Typically done in the medical bay.
  
  Authorized Personnel
  - The Chief Medical Officer, Senior Psychican, Medical Doctors, and Medical Interns are authorized to give all forms of treatment.
  - Paramedics are not authorized to give full treatment unless there are no free doctors in the medical bay.
  - Chemists are not authorized to give any form of treatment unless there are no free doctors in the medical bay or the station is in a state of crisis, in which care they are authorized to give emergency aid.
  - Anyone not on this list rendering aid in the medical bay should be removed from the treatment room unless it is a state of crisis.\n
  
  The Chief Medical Officer may authorize any level of treatment to specific individuals if they see fit.

 ## Uniform

  [color=green]Green[/color]: Medical staff should be wearing at least one identifiable piece of medical insignia. This can be either attire that is commonly associated with medical or pieces of medical clothing that directly show medical symbols.

  [color=red]Red[/color]: Medical staff should be wearing multiple pieces of medical insignia that can be identified at a quick glance. At least one part should be medical clothing that directly shows medical symbols, the rest can be attire that is commonly associated with medical.

  ## Gear

  [color=green]Green[/color]: Medical staff are authorized to use any standard issue equipment. Basic levels of PPE, such as latex gloves and sterile masks are recommended.

  [color=violet]Violet[/color]: All medical staff are required to wear the highest level of PPE accessible to them. If the disease at hand is identified, wear all types of gear that are known to protect you. Proper cleaning and decontamination gear should be stocked in the medical bay.

  [color=yellow]Yellow[/color]: Medical staff should have emergency oxygen gear on their person. Paramedics are advised to don their voidsuit.

  ## Triage

  [color=green]Green[/color]: Medical Staff > Staff with the most life threatening conditions.

  [color=blue]Blue[/color]: Medical Staff > Command Staff > Security Staff > Staff with the most life threatening conditions.

  [color=violet]Violet[/color]: Medical Staff > Sick or diseased staff > Staff with the most life threatening conditions.

  [color=yellow]Yellow[/color]: Medical Staff > Engineering Staff > Command Staff > Staff with the most life threatening conditions.

  [color=pink]Gamma[/color]: Direct Central Command assets > Medical Staff > Command Staff > Security Staff > Staff with the most life threatening conditions.

  [color=darkred]Delta[/color]:\n
  [bold]Outside safe locations[/bold]: Staff with the most movement hindering conditions.\n
  [bold]Inside safe locations[/bold]: Medical Staff > Staff with the most life threatening conditions.
</Document>
