<Document>
  # Science

  The standard procedures followed by science staff on any uniform NT station. The Research Director can edit, make additions, and make exceptions to their station's science operating procedures whenever they please as long as a copy of the changes is forwarded to the Captain's fax machine and another laid out in the science break room or other main room. The captain may veto any change made by the RD if they see fit. Anyone considered under the science department is required to follow this document.


  ## Silicon Uploading

  All silicon law changes, AI uploading, or AI termination must be agreed upon by both the Research Director and Captain. Unless hasty AI removal is a dire requirement to preserve the life of crew.


  ## Silicon Malfunctions (NE)
  
  If any onboard silicon is not functioning as intended, it should be quickly assessed as to how problematic the malfunction could be. If the malfunction is deemed problematic to the crew by any scientist, operations to repair the issue should begin.
  
  However if it is deemed unrepairable and problematic, the Research Director and Captain may agree to remove the Silicon in question, take out its brain or install it to an intellicard, store it in a safe location, fax Central Command about the issue, and hand it off to Central Command upon arrival. NT will run the silicon through diagnostics and bring it back into service when it has passed all trials.


  ## Silicon Assignment

  When giving a borg a new departmental chassis, Scientists must first ensure the relevant Department Head or 2IC is made aware of the reassignment and approves of it. Similar to how job hirings are handled.


  ## Research Operations

  Scientists are authorized and encouraged to perform experiments of all sorts. Tests do not require approval unless they are using restricted gear or substances. Tests must follow all Research Restrictions or they will be terminated. The Research Director may also veto an experiment at any point if they see fit.


  ## Research Restrictions

  The following list covers all the restrictions for Research Operations in place by default. If an experiment is found to be violating one of these restrictions it is automatically aborted, all staff are expected to stop taking part, and security may charge everyone involved accordingly.

  - The Research Director must be made aware of all testing.
  - Tests must be conducted within the confines of a controlled science environment or off-site.
  - Destructive objects must be tested in a reinforced, mostly explosion proof, environment or off-site.
  - Researchers must not be test subjects of their own experiments.
  - All sentient humanoid test subjects must consent to testing.
  - All sentient humanoid test subjects must be in a stable mental state.
  - All sentient humanoid test subjects must not face an undue risk to life or limb.
  - If a sentient humanoid test subject is injured they must be adequately treated.
  - If a sentient humanoid test subject asks for an experiment to cease the test must be aborted.
</Document>
